

## Shivam Nirhali

**Date of birth:** 22/08/1994 | **Nationality:** Indian | **Gender** Male | (+49) 016092125463 |

srnirhali@uni-koblenz.de | Weißenthurmer Str. 14, 56070, Koblenz, Germany

About me: An aspiring student pursuing an M.Sc. in Web and Data Science with a skillset in Java and Python programming language. Having 2+ years of experience as a Full-stack Developer in the IT industry. Self-organized and composed of working standards.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

01/04/2021 – CURRENT – Koblenz, Germany
STUDENT ASSISTANT – UNIVERSITY OF KOBLENZ-LANDAU

Examining student's Assignment for the Semantic Web course.

20/02/2017 - 19/09/2019 - Pune, India

PROJECT ENGINEER - CENTRE FOR DEVELOPMENT OF ADVANCED COMPUTING (CDAC)

- Full Stack Development/Management of Web Application and APIs.
- Development and Management of Android Application.
- Data Analyst and System Admin for Digital signature project.

## EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/09/2019 - CURRENT

MASTER OF SCIENCE (MSC) - University Of Koblenz-Landau

01/08/2016 - 31/01/2017

**PG-DIPLOMA IN ADVANCED COMPUTING** – Center for Development of Advanced Computing (CDAC)

01/08/2012 - 01/06/2016

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING - Savitribai Phule Pune University

## PUBLICATIONS

Data Security Using Text-Based Graphical Password and QR Code.

International Journal of Engineering Science and Computing(IJESC) 2015

# PROJECTS

# **Automatic Detection of Model Transformation Intents**

- Researched and Implemented classification model for Model Transformation Intents.
- Used nltk library for Natural Language processing to clean the data.
- Implemented and evaluated 9 different ML algorithms for classification including Neural Network.
- Used multiple concepts from Sklearn python lib such as Feature Extraction, Pipeline, Confusion Matrix, etc.

## **COVID-19 Prediction (Academic)**

- Data processing, analysis, Visualization, and Linear Regression based prediction.
- Developed Covid-19 cases prediction using Linear Regression model in python.
- Technologies Used Apache spark, pandas, geopandas, Matplotlib.

#### J2EE Electronic Voting System (Academic)

- Development of web application on J2EE Architecture.
- Working with MySQL database, hibernate ORM, Enterprise Java Beans used for backend, and frontend support by JSF and Bootfaces.

#### **ASP Integration Gateway**

- Development and Design of a web-based Client Onboarding system using Spring MVC and PostgreSQL database.
- The onboarding process improved by 30%.

#### **BOL Android Messaging Application**

- Prototype using open-source Conversation app.
- Development of android messaging application with end-to-end encryption using a signal protocol.
- Also configured and deployed ejabberd server.

### DIGITAL SKILLS

## **Programming Languages**

Python | Java | C#

# Technologies/Framework

Numpy | Pandas | AngularJS | CSS | HTML | SQL | Natural Language Processing (NLP) | Git | Machine Learning | Spring Boot/MVC | Scikit-Learn | Docker

### **Environment/Tools**

Linux | Windows | Eclipse | Visual Studio | Pycharm | Jupyter

## LANGUAGE SKILLS

## Mother tongue(s): HINDI

### Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C1	C1	C1	C1	C1
GERMAN	A1	A1	A1	A1	A1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user